<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>career &#8211; Freaklac</title>
	<atom:link href="https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/tag/career/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/</link>
	<description>Freak on the world</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 08:18:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/freaklac-black-150x150.jpg</url>
	<title>career &#8211; Freaklac</title>
	<link>https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>If you are not interested in engineering but joined an engineering</title>
		<link>https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/if-you-are-not-interested-in-engineering/</link>
					<comments>https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/if-you-are-not-interested-in-engineering/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[prakash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 12:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[not interested engineering]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/?p=129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction: What you want to do if you are not interested in engineering, but you have already joined an engineering college ?? If you like the course and want to be an engineer, then You can use the four years to improve your technical knowledge and explore your career options related to the field of&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/if-you-are-not-interested-in-engineering/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">If you are not interested in engineering but joined an engineering</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-ht-block-toc  is-style-outline htoc htoc--position-wide toc-list-style-plain" data-htoc-state="expanded"><span class="htoc__title"><span class="ht_toc_title">Table of Contents</span><span class="htoc__toggle"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="16" height="16"><g fill="#444"><path d="M15 7H1c-.6 0-1 .4-1 1s.4 1 1 1h14c.6 0 1-.4 1-1s-.4-1-1-1z"></path><path d="M15 1H1c-.6 0-1 .4-1 1s.4 1 1 1h14c.6 0 1-.4 1-1s-.4-1-1-1zM15 13H1c-.6 0-1 .4-1 1s.4 1 1 1h14c.6 0 1-.4 1-1s-.4-1-1-1z"></path></g></svg></span></span><div class="htoc__itemswrap"><ul class="ht_toc_list"><li class=""><a href="#htoc-introduction">Introduction:</a></li><li class=""><a href="#htoc-basically-why-the-students-are-not-interested-in-engineering">Why the students are not interested in engineering?</a></li><li class=""><a href="#htoc-my-suggestion">My suggestion:</a><ul class="ht_toc_child_list"><li class=""><a href="#htoc-try-to-place-a-company">Try to place a company</a></li><li class=""><a href="#block-fe278650-f9b7-4d73-82fa-88abffa1905d">Fun tip: </a></li><li class=""><a href="#block-fe278650-f9b7-4d73-82fa-88abffa1905d1">Serious Tip: </a></li></ul></li><li class=""><a href="#htoc-take-up-an-internship">Take up an internship:</a></li><li class=""><a href="#htoc-a-final-note-for-you-guys">A final note for you guys:</a></li></ul></div></div>



<h2 id="htoc-introduction">Introduction:</h2>



<p>What you want to do if you are not interested in engineering, but you have already joined an engineering college ??</p>



<p>If you like the course and want to be an engineer, then You can use the four years to improve your technical knowledge and explore your career options related to the field of engineering. </p>



<h2 id="htoc-basically-why-the-students-are-not-interested-in-engineering"><strong>Basically Why the students are not interested in engineering?</strong></h2>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>There are two kinds of students who hate engineering;</strong></p>



<ul><li>First would be the student who is forced to do engineering against his/her interest.</li><li>The second is the student who would have joined the course with some interest but over a period of time, the academic and college stress would have destroyed all the interest and liking the student had for the engineering degree.</li></ul>



<p>If you hate engineering and if you want to change track to a non-engineering field after college, then it is better to start planning from your first or second year itself. First, take a month to cry and cry as much as you want for taking engineering. After you have cried enough, wipe your tears away and realize rest of the years you going to love your work.</p>



<h2 id="htoc-my-suggestion"><strong>My suggestion</strong>:</h2>



<p> Did you know, why many students join engineering colleges ?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="600" height="335" src="https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/campus-placement.jpg" alt="Campus Placements " class="wp-image-136" srcset="https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/campus-placement.jpg 600w, https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/campus-placement-300x168.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<h3 id="htoc-try-to-place-a-company"><strong>Try to place a company</strong></h3>



<p>Even though you may not be interested in pursuing a career related to engineering or IT, it is financially safe to have a job at hand. Usually, there is a one year gap between your final semester exam and your date of joining. You can use this time to plan or prepare for your masters in a course where your interest lies. If your ultimate goal is to start your own business or social venture and if your parents are not financially well-off, you can use the employment to save for your future plans. However, you need to ensure that careers and the responsibilities of adult life.</p>



<h3 id="block-fe278650-f9b7-4d73-82fa-88abffa1905d"><strong>Fun tip: </strong></h3>



<p>If you get placed and reject the job offer, starting a non-engineering career path, adds glamour to your new venture. You can proudly say that you rejected a job offer at a Bangalore I.T. company to follow your passion.</p>



<h3 id="block-fe278650-f9b7-4d73-82fa-88abffa1905d1"><br><strong>Serious Tip:</strong> </h3>



<p>If your parents are very conservative and strict, you can use your campus placement as an escape route.</p>



<h3 id="htoc-try-to-place-a-company1"></h3>



<h2 id="htoc-take-up-an-internship"><strong>Take up an internship:</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="600" height="335" src="https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/take-up-an-internship.jpg" alt="Take up an internship" class="wp-image-140" srcset="https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/take-up-an-internship.jpg 600w, https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/take-up-an-internship-300x168.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p><br>There are two types of internships which you should take during college</p>



<ul><li><strong><strong>At a company related to your course of study.</strong></strong><br>This is important because it will help you understand whether your mindset is suitable to work in that field for the rest of your life. If you are pursuing an electronic engineering course, apply for an internship in electronic companies, where you will get hands-on experience in the job profile of an electronic engineer; and you can check whether you are ready to push yourself every day of your life to design machines, draw circuits and develop signal systems. If possible, talk openly with the company’s manager and get a practical understanding of what you will be doing when you work in such a company.</li><li> <strong>Take an internship in the field of your choice.</strong><br>This second type of internship is for the large majority of our youngster are doing. If you want to be a writer, work at a bookstore or a publishing company. If you want to be a photographer, apply for a part-time photography assignment in a local magazine, <a href="http://www.freelancer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">freelancer</a>. Whatever your field of interest is, take a list of companies in that field and check for the ones in your city or nearer to your college. Tell them that you are considering a future in their field and you feel an internship there will help you assess your potential.</li></ul>



<h2 id="htoc-a-final-note-for-you-guys"><strong>A final note for you guys</strong>:</h2>



<p>Whatever your choice is, do realize that deviating from engineering is nothing to be ashamed of. Obviously, when you shift from engineering to non-engineering field, there will be arguments like, ‘you wasted four years in engineering’, ‘you could have given the engineering seat to someone else’, ‘you should have taken up arts’, etc.</p>



<p>It is better to waste the four years in engineering and shift to your field of interest now, instead of regretting when you are in your 40year&#8217;s that you have ended up wasting your entire life in pursuing a career without any interest. Cheers! all the best for your career.</p>



<p>If you have any doubts feel free to <a href="https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/contact/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/contact/" rel="noreferrer noopener">contact me</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://prakash-aathi.github.io/freaklac/if-you-are-not-interested-in-engineering/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
